especially for young inmates.
خصوصاً للسجناء اليافعين.
New York state is one of only two in the U.S.
تعتقل ولاية نيويورك من أصل ولايتين فقط في الولايات المتحدة
that automatically arrests and tries 16- to 17-year-olds as adults.
وتحاكم بصورة تلقائية من هم بين عمر 16 -17 عاماً باعتبارهم بالغين.
This culture of violence takes these young people
ثقافة العنف هذه تزج بهولاء الشباب
and puts them in a hostile environment,
وتضعهم في بيئة عدائية،
and the correctional officers pretty much allow any and everything to go on.
ويسمح ضباط السجون بحدوث أي شيء وكل شيء.
There's not really much for these young people to do
في الحقيقة لا يوجد ما يفعله هولاء الشباب
to actually enhance their talent and actually rehabilitate them.
لتعزيز مهاراتهم وإعادة تأهيلهم.
Until we can raise the age of criminal responsibility to 18,
إلى أن نرفع سن المسؤولية الجنائية إلى 18 سنة،
we need to focus on changing the daily lives of these young people.
نحتاج إلى التركيز على تحسين حياة أولئك الشباب.
I know firsthand.
عشت التجربة بنفسي.
Before I ever turned 18,
قبل أن أبلغ سن الثامنة عشرة،
I spent approximately 400 days on Rikers Island,
قضيت مايقارب 400 يوم في سجن جزيرة رايركز
and to add to that
وبالإضافة لذلك،
I spent almost 300 days in solitary confinement,
قضيت نحو 300 يوم في الحبس الإنفرادي
and let me tell you this:
ودعوني أخبركم بهذا:
Screaming at the top of your lungs all day on your cell door
الصراخ بأعلى صوتك عند باب الزنزانة طوال اليوم
or screaming at the top of your lungs out the window,
أو الصراخ بأعلى صوتك من خلال النافذة،
it gets tiring.
أمر متعب.
Since there's not much for you to do while you're in there,
لأنه لا يوجد ماتفعله أثناء تواجدك هناك،
you start pacing back and forth in your cell,
فتقضي الوقت تطرق الزنزانة جيئة وذهابًا،
you start talking to yourself,
وتبدأ بالتحدث مع نفسك،
your thoughts start running wild,
حتى تعصف بك خيالاتك،
and then your thoughts become your own worst enemy.
فتُصبح أفكارك أسوأ أعداءك.
Jails are actually supposed to rehabilitate a person,
من المفترض أن تُعيد السجون تأهيل الشخص
not cause him or her to become more angry,
لا أن تدفعه إلى أن يصبح أكثر غضباً
frustrated, and feel more hopeless.
وإحباطاً، ويأسًا.
Since there's not a discharge plan put in place for these young people,
وبسبب عدم وجود أية خطة لإعادة إدماج هؤلاء الشباب،
they pretty much reenter society with nothing.
نجد أنهم يعودون للمجتمع بلا شيء.
And there's not really much for them to do to keep them from recidivating.
وفي حقيقة الأمر لا يوجد مايُفعل لإبعادهم عن الانتكاسة.
But it all starts with the C.O.s.
ولكن كل ذلك يبدأ من جانب ضباط السجن.
It's very easy for some people
من اليسير للبعض
to look at these correctional officers as the good guys
النظر لضباط السجون على أنهم أخيار
and the inmates as the bad guys,
والمساجين على أنهم سيئون،
or vice versa for some,
أو العكس للبعض،
but it's a little more than that.
ولكن المسألة أكبر من ذلك.
See, these C.O.s are normal, everyday people.
كما ترون، موظفو السجون أشخاص عاديون
They come from the same neighborhoods as the population they "serve."
يأتون من نفس الأحياء التي يأتي منها الناس الذين "يخدمونهم".
They're just normal people.
هم مجرد أُناس عاديين.
They're not robots, and there's nothing special about them.
إنهم ليسوا آليين، ولا يوجد شيء مميز فيهم.
They do pretty much everything anybody else in society does.
يفعلون مايفعله أي شخص آخر في المجتمع.
The male C.O.s want to talk and flirt with the female C.O.s.
الضباط الذكور يحبون التحدث مع الضباط الإناث ومعاكستهن.
They play the little high school kid games with each other.
يلعبون مع بعضهم ألعاب الأطفال بالثانوية.
They politic with one another.
إنهم رسميون مع بعضهم.
And the female C.O.s gossip to each other.
والضباط الإناث يتهامزون فيما بينهم.
and let me tell you about this one in particular named Monroe.
وأسمحوا لي أن أحدثكم عن شخص معين يدعى مونرو.
One day he pulled me in between the A and B doors
في أحد الأيام سحبني بين البابين أ و ب
which separate the north and south sides of our housing unit.
الذي يفصل الجانب الشمالي عن الجانب الجنوبي من وحدتنا السكنية.
He pulled me there because I had a physical altercation
سحبني هنالك لأني كنت في خضم مشاجرة
with another young man in my housing unit,
مع شاب آخر من نفس وحدتي السكنية،
and he felt, since there was a female officer working on the floor,
بما أنه كان هنالك ضابطة تعمل في الطابق
that I violated his shift.
فإنه أحس بأني انتهكت مناوبته.
So he punched me in my chest.
لذا قام بلكمي على صدري.
He kind of knocked the wind out of me.
وذلك نوعا ما قطع أنفاسي.
I wasn't impulsive, I didn't react right away,
لم أكن متهورًا، ولم تكن ردت فعلي مباشرة.
because I know this is their house.
ولأني أعلم أن هذا عرينهم،
I have no wins.
لم أكن لأفوز.
All he has to do is pull his pin and backup will come immediately.
وبمجرد أن ضغط على الزر جاءت المساعدة فورا.
So I just gave him a look in his eyes
حينها فقط رمقتُه بنظرة
and I guess he saw the anger and frustration just burning,
وأعتقد أنه رأى الغضب والإحباط يشعان مني،
and he said to me,
فقال لي،
"Your eyes are going to get you in a lot of trouble,
" عيناك ستقحمانك في الكثير من المشاكل،
because you're looking like you want to fight."
لأنه يبدو أنك تريد العراك."
So he commenced to taking off his utility belt,
حتى أنه بدأ بخلع حزامه،
he took off his shirt and his badge,
ثم خلع قميصه وشارته،
and he said, "We could fight."
وقال لي، "يمكننا القتال."
So I asked him, "You gonna hold it down?"
لذلك سألته:"هل ستبُقي عليه؟"
and you're not going to report it.
.ولا حتى ستبلغ عن ذلك.
He said, "Yeah, I'm gonna hold it down. You gonna hold it down?"
فأجاب: "نعم، سأبقي عليه . هل سوف تبقي عليه؟ "
I didn't even respond.
لم أجبه حتى.
I just punched him right in his face,
وقمت بلكمه مباشرة على وجهه
and we began fighting right then and there.
و حينها بدأنا العراك.
Towards the end of the fight, he slammed me up against the wall,
حينما شارف القتال على الإنتهاء قام بضربي بالجدار،
so while we were tussled up, he said to me, "You good?"
و بينما كنا ممسكين ببعضنا، قال لي: "أنت بخير؟
as if he got the best of me,
كما لو أنه نال مني،
but in my mind, I know I got the best of him,
ولكن في نفسي،أعلم تماماً أنني نلت منه.
so I replied very cocky,
لذا أجبت بغرور،
"Oh, I'm good, you good?"
" بالطبع أنا بخير، أنت بخير؟"
He said, "Yeah, I'm good, I'm good."
فأجاب، "نعم أنا بخير، أنا بخير."
We let go, he shook my hand, said he gave me my respect,
دعنا نذهب، تصافحنا مفيدًا بذلك أنه أعاد لي احترامي،
gave me a cigarette and sent me on my way.
قدم لي سيجارة وتركني لحال سبيلي.
Believe it or not, you come across some C.O.s on Rikers Island
صدق أو لاتصدق، حينما تصادف بعض ضباط السجن في جزيرة رايكرز
that'll fight you one-on-one.
سيتعاركون معك وجهاً لوجه.
They feel that they understand how it is,
يظنون أنهم يفهمون النظام،
and they feel that I'm going to meet you where you're at.
ويشعرون بأنني ذاهب لمقابلتهم أينما كانوا.
Since this is how you commonly handle your disputes,
بما أنكم تتعاملون مع نزاعاتكم بتلك الطريقة،
we can handle it in that manner.
فإننا سنتعامل معها بالطريقة ذاتها.
I walk away from it like a man, you walk away from it like a man,
خرجت من ذلك برأس مرفوع، أنت ستخرج من ذلك برأس مرفوع،
and that's it.
وهذا كل شيء.
Some C.O.s feel that they're jailing with you.
بعض الضباط يشعرون بأنهم محبوسون معك.
This is why they have that mentality and that attitude
لذا لديهم مثل هذه العقلية وذلك السلوك
and they go by that concept.
وهم يقبلون بتلك الفكرة.
In some instances, we're in it together with the C.O.s.
وفي بعض الحالات نحن مشتركون مع ضباط السجون في ذلك.
However, institutions need to give these correctional officers
بطبيعة الحال، يجب على المؤسسات أن تقدم لضباط الإصلاحيات
proper trainings on how to properly deal with the adolescent population,
التدريب المناسب على كيفية التعامل مع السجناء المراهقين،
and they also need to give them proper trainings
فضلاً عن التدريب المناسب
on how to deal with the mental health population as well.
على كيفية التعامل مع السجناء الذين يعانون من مشاكل نفسية.
These C.O.s play a big factor in these young people's lives
يؤدي ضباط السجن دورا مهما في حياة هؤلاء الشباب
for x amount of time until a disposition is reached on their case.
لمدة معينة حتى يتم حل قضيتهم.
so once they reenter back into society,
بحيث يفعلون شيئا إيجابيا،
A second big thing to help our teens in jails is better programming.
والأمر الثاني الذي يساعد المراهقين في السجن هو استخدام برنامج أفضل.
When I was on Rikers Island, the huge thing was solitary confinement.
عندما كنت في سجن جزيرة رايركرز، كان أسوأ شيء الحبس الانفرادي.
Solitary confinement was originally designed
قد تم تصميم الحبس الانفرادي في الأصل
to break a person mentally, physically and emotionally.
للتسبب في انهيار الشخص عقلياً، وعاطفياً و بدنياً.
The U.S. Attorney General recently released a report
أصدر النائب العام الأمريكي مؤخراً تقريراً
stating that they're going to ban solitary confinement
ينص على إيقاف الحبس الإنفرادي
in New York state for teens.
في ولاية نيويورك للأحداث.
One thing that kept me sane while I was in solitary confinement was reading.
ما منعني من حافة الجنون في السجن الإنفرادي أنني كنت أقرأ.
I tried to educate myself as much as possible.
حاولت أن أُعلم نفسي قدر المستطاع.
I read any and everything I could get my hands on.
قرأت أي شئ أمكنني الحصول عليه.
And aside from that, I wrote music and short stories.
إلى جانب لذلك، قمت بتأليف بعض الأغاني والقصص القصيرة.
for the kids that like to draw and have that talent,
للشباب الذين يحبون الرسم ولديهم هذه الموهبة،
and what about the young individuals that are musically inclined?
وماذا عن أولئك الذين يميلون إلى الموسيقى؟
How about a music program for them that actually teaches them
ماذا عن برنامج موسيقي يمكن في الحقيقة أن يعلمهم
how to write and make music?
كيفية كتابة وتأليف الموسيقى.
Just a thought.
مجرد فكرة.
When adolescents come to Rikers Island,
عندما يأتي المراهقون إلى سجن جزيرة رايكرز،
C74, RNDC is the building that they're housed in.
يقيمون في مباني مخصصة.
because you have a young individual coming in from the street
لأن الشباب الجدد القادمين من الشارع
thinking that they're tough,
يعتقدون بأنهم أشداء،
being surrounded by a bunch of other young individuals
كونهم محاطين بحفنة من الشباب الآخرين
from all of the five boroughs, and everybody feels that they're tough.
من بلدات نيويورك الخمسة، والكل يشعر بأنه قوي.
So now you have a bunch of young gentlemen poking their chests out
فالآن لديك مجموعة من الشباب يمشون بتعال،
feeling that I have to prove I'm equally as tough as you
ويعتقدون أن عليهم إثبات أنهم أقوياء مثلك
or I'm tougher than you, you and you.
أو أنهم أقوى منك ومن أي أحد.
But let's be honest:
ولكن لنكن صادقين:
That culture is very dangerous and damaging to our young people.
هذه الثقافة في غاية الخطورة ومدمرة لشبابنا.
We need to help institutions and these teens realize
يجب علينا أن نجعل المؤسسة وأولئك الشباب يُدركون
that they don't have to lead the previous lifestyle that they led
أنهم ليسوا بحاجة لمواصلة نمط حياتهم السابق
when they were on the street, that they can actually make a change.
عندما كانوا في الشارع، وأنهم قادرون على إحداث التغيير.
I used to hear dudes talking about when they get released from prison,
كثيراً ما سمعت الرجال يتحدثون قبل إطلاق سراحهم
what type of crimes they're going to commit
عن الجرائم سيقومون بإرتكابها
when they get back in the street.
عند عودتهم إلى الشوارع.
The conversations used to sound something like this:
تبدو المناقشات عادة مثل هذا:
for this, that and the third,"
لهذا، ولذلك وللآخر"
or, "My man over here got this connection for the low price.
أو، " صديقي هنا لديه معارفه وبسعر مخفض.
Let's exchange information,"
لنتبادل المعلومات،"
and, "When we hit the town, we're going to do it real big."
وقال "عندما نذهب إلى المدينة سوف نفعلها بصورة أكبر "
I used to hear these conversations and think to myself, "Wow,
كُنت أستمع لتلك المحادثات وأفكر متعجباً،
these dudes are really talking about going back in the street
هاؤلاء الرجال يتحدثون عن عودتهم إلى الشارع
and committing future crimes."
و إرتكاب جرائم جديدة ".
So I came up with a name for that:
لذا وضعت اسما لهذا:
I called it a go-back-to-jail-quick scheme
سميته - الخطة السريعة للعودة إلى السجن
because really, how long is that going to last?
لأنه حقا، كم سيقدر له الإستمرار؟
You get a retirement plan with that?
ألا تملك خطة تقاعد من ذلك؟
Nice little pension? 401(k)? 403(b)?
راتب تقاعدي جيد؟ 401 (k)؟ 403 (b)
You get health insurance? Dental?
هل لديك تأمين صحي؟ أو تأمين أسنان؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I will tell you this:
ولكن سأقول لكم هذا:
Being in jail and being in prison,
خلال وجودي في الحبس وفي السجن،
I came across some of the most intelligent, brilliant,
مر علي بعض من أذكى وأدهى
and talented people that I would ever meet.
و ألمع الشخصيات التي قابلتها في حياتي.
I've seen individuals take a potato chip bag
رأيت أحدهم يأخذ كيس رقائق البطاطس
and turn it into the most beautiful picture frame.
ويحوله إلى إطار صورة أكثر من رائع.
I've seen individuals take the state soap that's provided for free
رأيت أحدهم يأخد الصابون المجاني المقدم لنا
and turn them into the most beautiful sculptures
ويحوله إلى منحوته ساحرة
that would make Michelangelo look like a kindergartner made it.
من شأنها أن تجعل مايكل أنجلو يبدو كأنه طفل صغير.
At the age of 21, I was in a maximum-security prison
في عمر 21، كنت في سجن مشدد الحراسة
called Elmira Correctional Facility.
يدعى مرفق إلميرا الإصلاحي.
I just came out of the weight shack from working out,
كُنت خارجًا للتو من صالة الألعاب الرياضية
and I saw an older gentleman that I knew standing in the middle of the yard
لمحت رجلا مسنا محترما كنت أعرفه يقف في وسط الفناء
just looking up at the sky.
كان ينظر إلى السماء.
Mind you, this older gentlemen was serving a 33-and-a-third-to-life sentence
تذكروا، هذا الرجل المسن محكوم بـ 33 سنة مع السجن المؤبد
in which he already had served 20 years of that sentence.
وقضى 20 سنة من ذلك الحكم.
So I walk up to him and I said,
إقتربت من وسألته،
"O.G., what's going on, man, you good?"
"عمي، مالذي يجري، هل أنت بخير؟"
He looked at me, and he said, "Yeah, I'm good, young blood."
وقال وهو يتطلع في وجهي : " نعم، أنا بخير، أيها الفتى."
I'm like, "So what are you looking up at the sky for, man?
قلت له، "لماذا إذن تنظر في السماء يا رجل؟
What's so fascinating up there?"
ما الذي يثيرك هناك؟ "
He said, "You look up and you tell me what you see."
أجاب، " أُنظر وقل لي ماذا ترى."
He said, "All right. What else do you see?"
قال لي، "حسناً. ماذا ترى بخلاف ذلك؟
At that time, it was a plane passing by.
في تلك الحظة كانت هناك طائرة عابرة.
I said, "All right, I see an airplane."
قلت،"حسناً، إنى أرى طائرة."
He said, "Exactly, and what's on that airplane?" "People."
وقال: "بالضبط، وما هو على متن تلك الطائرة؟ " "أشخاص".
"Exactly. Now where's that plane and those people going?"
"هذا صحيح. الآن قل لي أين تذهب هذه الطائرة بالأشخاص؟ "
"I don't know. You know?
"أنا لا أعلم. هلتعلم أنت ؟
Please let me know if you do. Then let me get some lottery numbers."
قل لي إذا كنت تعرف. ثم دعني أجلب بعضا من ورق اليانصيب ".
He said, "You're missing the big picture, young blood.
قال، "أنت لاترى المضمون الحقيقي، أيها الفتى.
That plane with those people is going somewhere,
هذه الطائرة مع أولئك الأشخاص ذاهبة إلى مكان ما،
while we're here stuck.
بينما نحن عالقون هُنا.
The big picture is this:
المضمون الحقيقي هو:
That plane with those people going somewhere,
هذه الطائرة مع أولئك الأشخاص ذاهبة إلى مكان ما،
that's life passing us by while we behind these walls, stuck."
الحياة تمر بينما نحن خلف الجدران، عالقون".
Ever since that day,
منذ ذلك اليوم فصاعدًا،
that sparked something in my mind and made me know I had to make a change.
شيء لمع في ذهني جعلني أدرك أنه علي إحداث تغيير.
Growing up, I was always a good, smart kid.
عند نشأتي كنت دوماَ ذلك الطفل الجيد والذكي
Some people would say I was a little too smart for my own good.
قد يقول البعض أنني كنت قليلاً أكثر ذكاء مما ينبغي.
I had dreams of becoming an architect or an archaeologist.
كان هنالك حُلم يراودني بأني سأصبح مهندسا معماريا أو عالم آثار.
Currently, I'm working at the Fortune Society,
حالياً أعمل في جمعية فورتشن،
which is a reentry program,
وهو برنامج لإعادة التأهيل،
and I work with people as a case manager that are at high risk for recidivism.
حيث أعمل كمسئول اجتماعي مع الناس الذين هم عرضة لخطر الانتكاس.
So I connect them with the services that they need
حيث أربطهم بالخدمات ذات الصلة
once they're released from jail and prison
بمجرد خروجهم من الحبس والسجن
so they can make a positive transition back into society.
لصنع تحول إيجابي لهم في المجتمع.
If I was to see my 15-year-old self today,
إذا كنت قادرًا اليوم على رؤية ذاتي قبل 15 سنة
I would sit down and talk to him and try to educate him
كنت سأحادثها في محاولة لتثقيفها
and I would let him know, "Listen, this is me. I'm you.
وأود أن أقول، "اسمع، هذا أنا. أنا أنت.
This is us. We are one.
هذا نحن. نحن واحد.
before you do it because I already did it,
قبل أن تفعل ذلك، لأنني قد فعلته مُسبقاً ".
and I would encourage him not to hang out with x, y and z people.
وأود أن أشجعها على عدم تكوين صداقات مع أولئك النوع من الناس.
I would tell him not to be in such-and-such place.
و أن أقول لها أن لا تتواجد في هذا المكان أو ذاك.
I would tell him, keep your behind in school, man,
وأود أن أقول لها أن تبقى في المدرسة،
because that's where you need to be,
لأنها يجب أن تكون هناك،
because that's what's going to get you somewhere in life.
لأن هذا سيساعدها في الحصول على مكان في الحياة.
This is the message that we should be sharing
هذه هي الرسالة التي يجب أن ننشرها
with our young men and young women.
وسط شبابنا وشاباتنا.
We shouldn't be treating them as adults and putting them in cultures of violence
لا أن نعاملهم كما لو كانوا بالغين وإقحامهم في ثقافة العنف
that are nearly impossible for them to escape.
التي يكاد يستحيل عليهم الخروج منها.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)